1日目は白紙の日だった。
艾瑟雅：第一天是空虚的一天。
The first day was a blank day.
何も覚えていない。何も分からない。
艾瑟雅：什么都不记得，什么都不知道。
I remembered nothing. I understood nothing.
何一つ持たないまま、あたしは目覚めた。
艾瑟雅：我就这样一无所有地醒来了。
Without a single thing to my name, I woke up.
ここ、どこ？
艾瑟雅：这里……是哪里？
Where... am I?
あたしは……あたしを……
艾瑟雅：我……我……
I... I...
鏡。
艾瑟雅：镜子。
A mirror.
あたしの顔。
艾瑟雅：我的脸。
My face.
あれ、でも何かが……
艾瑟雅：奇怪，总觉得哪里……
Wait, but something...
あら、目が覚めた？
妮戈兰：哎呀，你醒了吗？
Oh, you're awake?
おっとっと。
妮戈兰：喔哆哆。
Whoops-a-daisy.
こらこら、まだ起き上がっちゃだめよ、アイセア。
妮戈兰：好啦好啦，还不能坐起来哦，艾瑟雅。
Now now, you shouldn't try to get up yet, Ithea.
すごい熱出てるんだから。
妮戈兰：你还在发高烧呢。
You have a very high fever.
アイセア……
艾瑟雅：艾瑟雅……
Ithea...
あたしの名前、なのかな。
艾瑟雅：那是……我的名字吗？
Is that... my name?
だから寝てなさいってば！
妮戈兰：所以我说让你躺好啦！
I told you, stay in bed!
ちゃんとしないと、治るものも治らないでしょ。
妮戈兰：不好好休息的话，病可不会好哦。
If you don't behave, you'll never get better.
頭がぼんやりして、何も思い出せない。
艾瑟雅：脑袋昏沉沉的，什么也想不起来。
My head is hazy, I can't remember anything.
ん？
妮戈兰：嗯？
Hmm?
あたしは誰だ？
艾瑟雅：我是……谁？
Who am I?
うーん、これは重症ね。
妮戈兰：嗯……这可真是病得不轻呢。
Hmm, this is quite serious.
あなたはアイセア。
妮戈兰：你是艾瑟雅。
You are Ithea.
アイセア・マイゼ・ヴァルガリス。
妮戈兰：艾瑟雅·麦杰·瓦尔卡利斯。
Ithea Myse Valgulious.
12歳。成体になったばかりの妖精。
妮戈兰：12岁。刚成为成体的小妖精。
12 years old. A Fairy who has just become an adult.
アイセア。
艾瑟雅：艾瑟雅。
Ithea.
あたしはそんな名前じゃ……
艾瑟雅：我不叫这个名字……
I don't have a name like that...
と言われても、事実はあなたはアイセアなの。
妮戈兰：就算你这么说，但事实就是你叫艾瑟雅哦。
Even if you say that, the fact is that you are Ithea.
そして大事な大事な、うちの子です。
妮戈兰：而且是我们最重要的、最重要的孩子。
And you are our precious, precious daughter.
お？
艾瑟雅：哦？
Oh?
嘘だと思うなら、鏡見てみなさい。
妮戈兰：不信的话，就照照镜子看吧。
If you think I'm lying, look in the mirror.
ちょっと血色悪いけど、いつものあなたの顔があるわよ。
妮戈兰：虽然脸色有点差，但那就是你平时的样子。
Your color is a bit poor, but there is the face you've always had.
これ、誰の顔？
艾瑟雅：这是……谁的脸？
Whose face is this?
誰って、あなた自身の顔よ。もちろん。
妮戈兰：什么谁的，当然是你自己的脸啊。
Whose? It's your own face, of course.
そんなことまで思い出せない？
妮戈兰：连这种事都想不起来了吗？
Can't you even remember that much?
あたし、こんな顔知らない。
艾瑟雅：我……根本不认识这张脸。
I... I don't know this face.
こらこら、考え込まないの。
妮戈兰：好啦好啦，别想太多了。
Now now, don't overthink it.
熱が上がったら大変でしょ？
妮戈兰：要是烧得更厉害了怎么办？
It'll be bad if your fever goes up again, right?
あんまり無茶ばかりしてると、茹でて食べちゃうわよ。
妮戈兰：要是再这么胡来，我就把你煮了吃掉哦。
If you keep pushing yourself, I'll boil you and eat you up.
食べっ！？
艾瑟雅：吃……吃掉！？
Eat... me?!
寝つくまで、手握っていてあげましょうか？
妮戈兰：要不要我握着你的手，直到你睡着为止？
Shall I hold your hand until you fall asleep?
その……あなたの言うアイセアは……
艾瑟雅：那个……你所说的那个艾瑟雅……
That... Ithea you mentioned...
愛されてるの？
艾瑟雅：是被爱着的吗？
Is she loved?
当たり前じゃないの。
妮戈兰：那不是理所当然的吗。
Of course she is.
そっか。
艾瑟雅：这样啊。
I see.
だったらあたし、アイセアでいいかな。
艾瑟雅：那……我就当艾瑟雅好了。
In that case, I guess I can be Ithea.
眠れそう？
妮戈兰：能睡着吗？
Do you think you can sleep?
ああ。
艾瑟雅：嗯。
Yeah.
気分は悪いけど、心地はいい。
艾瑟雅：虽然感觉不太舒服，但心情并不坏。
I feel sick, but it's comfortable here.
2日目は困惑の日だった。
艾瑟雅：第二天是困惑的一天。
The second day was a day of confusion.
熱はなかなか下がらず、意識もはっきりしない。
艾瑟雅：热度一直不退，意识也模糊不清。
The fever didn't go down, and my consciousness was unclear.
それでも、一つだけ確信できることがあった。
艾瑟雅：尽管如此，还是有一件事可以确信。
Still, there was one thing I could be sure of.
自分は今、とんでもなくおかしな状況にある。
艾瑟雅：我现在的处境，简直荒诞透顶。
I am currently in an incredibly strange situation.
成体になりたての妖精にね、たまにいるんだって。
妮戈兰：据说在刚成熟的小妖精里，偶尔会有这样的情况。
I heard it happens sometimes with Fairies who just became adults.
急な変化に体が戸惑って、熱を出しちゃう子。
妮戈兰：身体无法适应突如其来的变化，于是发起了烧。
Children whose bodies are confused by the sudden change and run a fever.
でも、あなたみたいにそれで倒れちゃうってのは、
妮戈兰：不过像你这样直接昏过去的，
But it's quite rare for someone to collapse from it,
なかなかないみたい。
妮戈兰：好像还挺少见的呢。
like you did.
おー。
艾瑟雅：喔。
Oh.
ま、寝てれば治るものなんだから、今はしっかり休み。
妮戈兰：嘛，睡一觉就会好的，现在就好好休息吧。
Well, you'll recover if you sleep, so get plenty of rest for now.
食欲はある？
妮戈兰：有食欲吗？
Do you have an appetite?
後で食べやすいものを持ってきてあげる。
妮戈兰：待会儿我给你带点容易入口的东西来。
I'll bring you something easy to eat later.
あ、あの……今年って何年？
艾瑟雅：那、那个……今年是哪一年？
Um, what year is it?
あら、変なこと聞くのね。435年よ。
妮戈兰：哎呀，问的问题真奇怪。435年哦。
My, what a strange thing to ask. It's year 435.
ほう。
艾瑟雅：喔……
I see.
あなたの誕生日まであとちょっと。
妮戈兰：离你的生日也不远了。
It's almost your birthday.
誕生日。生まれた日。
艾瑟雅：生日。出生的日子。
Birthday. The day I was born.
さ、ちゃんと元気になってお祝いしないとね。
妮戈兰：好啦，得快点好起来庆祝才行。
So, you have to get well so we can celebrate.
祝う。
艾瑟雅：庆祝。
Celebrate.
それじゃ、ちゃんと寝てるのよ。
妮戈兰：那么，要乖乖睡觉哦。
Well then, make sure you sleep well.
おかしい。
艾瑟雅：不对劲。
It's strange.
こりゃ一体どういうこと？
艾瑟雅：这到底是怎么一回事？
What on earth is going on?
熱が引いて、少しだけ昔のことを思い出した。
艾瑟雅：烧退了一些后，我想起了一点过去的事。
The fever broke, and I remembered a little bit of the past.
あたしはナサニア。ナサニア・ウィル・パーチェム。
艾瑟雅：我是纳萨尼亚。纳萨尼亚·威尔·帕齐姆。
I am Nasania. Nasania Wil Percem.
大陸軍を守るために敵と戦って、死んだはずの妖精兵。
艾瑟雅：本该为了守护大陆军战斗而死的妖精兵。
A fairy soldier who should have died fighting to protect the Continental Army.
あの女の言うアイセアとかいうのは別人だ。
艾瑟雅：那个女人所说的艾瑟雅是另一个人。
That Ithea woman that lady spoke of is someone else.
そのあたしがどうして生き延びているのか？
艾瑟雅：那样的我，究竟是怎么活下来的？
So why is it that I've survived?
あたしの知る妖精倉庫とはまるで違うこの部屋は何なのか？
艾瑟雅：这个和我知道的妖精仓库截然不同的房间又是怎么回事？
And what is this room, so different from the Fairy Warehouse I know?
今のあたしの顔と体はどうやらアイセアとかいう子供のものらしい。
艾瑟雅：看来我现在这副容貌和身体，是那个叫艾瑟雅的小孩的。
It seems my current face and body belong to that child called Ithea.
なんでそんなことになっているのか。
艾瑟雅：为什么会变成这个样子？
Why did things turn out this way?
そもそもそのアイセア本人は今どこにいるのか。
艾瑟雅：说到底，那个艾瑟雅本人现在在哪？
In the first place, where is that Ithea herself right now?
謎だらけだ。
艾瑟雅：全是谜团。
It's full of mysteries.
手がかりの一つも掴まんことにゃ、おちおち寝てもいられない。
艾瑟雅：不找到一点线索的话，根本没法安心睡觉。
I can't just lie here and sleep without catching a single clue.
お。
艾瑟雅：喔？
Oh?
日記か。
艾瑟雅：日记吗？
A diary?
アイセアの。
艾瑟雅：艾瑟雅的日记。
Ithea's.
へえ、こんな子だったんだ。
艾瑟雅：嘿……原来她是这样的孩子啊。
Heh, so she was this kind of girl.
自分の中だけで色々抱え込みがちで。
艾瑟雅：总是习惯把各种事情憋在心里。
Always prone to keeping things bottled up inside.
あたしとはだいぶ違うね。
艾瑟雅：和我完全不一样呢。
Quite different from me.
アイセア、ネフレンだけど、まだ起きてる？
奈芙莲：艾瑟雅，我是奈芙莲，你还醒着吗？
Ithea, it's Nephren. Are you still awake?
ちょ、ちょっと待て！
艾瑟雅：等、等等！
W-Wait a second!
ナイグラートに頼まれてオートミール持ってきた。
奈芙莲：受妮戈兰之托，把燕麦粥送过来了。
Nygglatho asked me to bring some oatmeal.
取り込み中？
奈芙莲：你正忙吗？
Are you busy?
いや、別にそういうわけじゃ……
艾瑟雅：不，倒也不是那样……
No, not exactly...
日記書いてた？
奈芙莲：你在写日记吗？
Were you writing in your diary?
ああ、うん。書いてたっていうか、読んでたっていうか。
艾瑟雅：啊，嗯。与其说是写，不如说是读……
Ah, yeah. Well, more like reading than writing.
後にしなさい。今はちゃんと寝る。食べる。
奈芙莲：晚点再说。现在要好好睡觉、吃饭。
Save it for later. Now, sleep. Eat.
そして元気いなること。
奈芙莲：然后早点康复。
And get well soon.
ほら、ベッドに戻って。
奈芙莲：来吧，快回床上。
Come on, back to bed.
仰せの通り。
艾瑟雅：遵命。
As you wish.
残さず食べる。
奈芙莲：要全部吃掉。
Eat it all up.
いただきます。
艾瑟雅：我开动了。
Thank you for the food.
病人専用、特別レシピ。
奈芙莲：病人专用特别食谱。
A special recipe for patients.
心して食べるべき。
奈芙莲：你要用心吃掉。
You should eat it with gratitude.
なんか甘くて、うまいな。
艾瑟雅：感觉甜滋滋的，真好吃啊。
It's kind of sweet and tasty.
ん？
艾瑟雅：嗯？
Hmm?
あ、いや、うまいですね。
艾瑟雅：啊，不，是“很好吃”呢。
Ah, I mean, it's delicious.
変なアイセア。
奈芙莲：奇怪的艾瑟雅。
Strange Ithea.
3日目は学習と演技の日だった。
艾瑟雅：第三天是学习和演技的一天。
The third day was a day for learning and acting.
この場所の主である本物のアイセアの日記を読んだ。
艾瑟雅：我读了这房间的主人——真正的艾瑟雅的日记。
I read the diary of the real Ithea, the owner of this place.
彼女はどうやら、明るくて喧しくて、
艾瑟雅：她似乎是个开朗、吵闹，
It seems she was the type of girl who was cheerful and noisy,
あまり本心で話さないタイプの子であったらしい。
艾瑟雅：但不太说真心话的孩子。
and didn't really speak her true feelings.
おーっすアイセア！クトリお姉さんのお見舞いだよ。
珂朵莉：哟，艾瑟雅！珂朵莉姐姐来看望你啦！
Yo, Ithea! Big sister Chtholly is here to visit!
大人しく寝てるかい？おっと、予想よりタフな反応。
珂朵莉：有乖乖睡觉吗？喔，反应比预想的还要硬朗。
Are you sleeping quietly? Whoops, a tougher reaction than expected.
なんだ、案外元気そうじゃない。
珂朵莉：什么嘛，看起来意外地精神呢。
Well, you look surprisingly energetic.
お、ああ。そう、すかね？
艾瑟雅：哦、啊。是，是吗？
O-Oh, yeah. You think so?
だいぶ熱出してるって聞いてたから、
珂朵莉：因为听说你烧得很厉害，
I heard you had a pretty high fever,
結構心配してたんだけどね。
珂朵莉：所以还挺担心的。
so I was quite worried.
ほら、あんたって線が細いし儚い感じだし。
珂朵莉：因为你看上去弱不禁风，给人一种虚幻的感觉。
See, you're slim and have a fragile feel to you.
体力あんま無さそうだし、風邪もズルズル長引きそうだし。
珂朵莉：体力好像也不怎么样，感冒估计也会拖很久。
You don't seem to have much stamina, and it felt like a cold would drag on.
いやまあ、妖精兵は動けなくなったらそれでお役御免。
珂朵莉：哎呀不过，妖精兵一旦不能动了，使命也就结束了。
Anyway, once a Fairy Soldier can't move, they're relieved of duty.
ですから、熱が出てるくらいのこと。
珂朵莉：所以，区区发烧这种小事，
So, just a little fever...
あんまり寝込んでばかりも……
珂朵莉：可不能一直躺着不……
Don't just stay in bed...
こらこら、あんまりそういうこと言うと、ナイグラートが泣くでしょ？
珂朵莉：喂喂，你要是说这种话，妮戈兰会哭的吧？
Hey now, if you say things like that, Nygglatho will cry, right?
あたしたちがこういう生活を送れるようになるまで、
珂朵莉：在我们可以像这样生活之前，
Until we were able to lead a life like this,
あいつがどれだけ頑張ってくれたと思ってんのさ？
珂朵莉：你觉得她付出了多少努力啊？
do you have any idea how hard she worked for us?
ナイグラート。
艾瑟雅：妮戈兰。
Nygglatho.
曰く、愛情に甘えるのは子供の義務ってことらしいわよ。
珂朵莉：据说，撒娇依赖这份爱，是小孩子的义务哦。
As she says, it seems indulging in affection is a child's duty.
そこに関しちゃ、あたしも同意見。
珂朵莉：关于这一点，我也持相同意见。
In that regard, I agree with her.
やっと成体になれたからって、気負ってるのかもしれないけど、
珂朵莉：虽然可能是因为终于成熟了而有些自满，
You might be feeling a bit high and mighty just because you've become an adult,
あんまり一足飛びに大人になろうとするもんじゃないよ。
珂朵莉：但也别急着一下子就想变成大人呀。
but you shouldn't try to become a grown-up all at once.
愛情に甘える、か。
艾瑟雅：依赖这份爱……吗。
Indulge in affection, huh.
ん、どうした？
珂朵莉：嗯？怎么了？
Hmm, what's wrong?
ああ、いや。なんでもないっす。
艾瑟雅：啊，不。没什么。
Ah, no. It's nothing.
ふーん。
珂朵莉：哼——
Hmm.
ま、んじゃおやすみ。
珂朵莉：嘛，那么晚安。
Well then, goodnight.
どうにもここの倉庫は調子が狂うね。
艾瑟雅：这里的仓库还真是让人感到不对劲。
This warehouse really throws me off.
さて、日記の続きを読む前に、先に何か食いもんでも探してくるか。
艾瑟雅：那么，在继续读日记之前，先去找点吃的吧。
Now, before I read the rest of the diary, I'll go find something to eat.
ほらクトリ、水瓶早く運んで。
奈芙莲：珂朵莉，快把水瓶搬走。
Come on Chtholly, hurry up and carry the water jars.
ちょ、ちょっと待てネフレン、これ重いんだから。
珂朵莉：等、等一下奈芙莲，这很重的。
Wait a sec, Nephren, these are heavy.
あれ、アイセア？
珂朵莉：哎，艾瑟雅？
Oh, Ithea?
お、こんなところで何してるの君、まだ体治ってないんでしょ？
珂朵莉：喔，你在这儿干嘛呢，身体还没好吧？
Oh, what are you doing here? You haven't recovered yet, have you?
あ、小腹が空いたので、ちょっと何か摘み食いを。
艾瑟雅：啊，有点饿了，想来偷吃点东西。
Ah, I was a bit hungry, so I came to grab a snack.
あー、そんなの呼んでくれれば誰かが持っていくから。
珂朵莉：啊，那种事只要叫一声，谁都会给你送去的。
Ah, if you'd just called, someone would have brought you something.
病人はちゃんと寝てなきゃだめでしょ？
珂朵莉：病人必须要好好睡觉才行吧？
Patients have to stay in bed, don't they?
いや、それには及ばないっす。
艾瑟雅：不，不劳费心了。
No, that's not necessary.
君ももう成体妖精兵なんだから、大人として
珂朵莉：你现在已经是成体妖精兵了，作为大人，
You're a grown-up Fairy Soldier now, so as an adult...
ティアットたちに恥ずかしくないようにしなきゃいけないんだからね。
珂朵莉：可不能在缇亚忒她们面前丢脸。
...you have to act so you're not an embarrassment to Tiat and the others.
ほら、すぐに何か作ってきてあげるから、君は戻って戻って。
珂朵莉：好啦，我马上给你做点吃的，你快回去回去。
Look, I'll make you something right away, so you go back, go back.
クトリは真面目っすね。
艾瑟雅：珂朵莉真的很认真呢。
Chtholly is so serious.
違うから。君たちが不真面目なだけ、私、普通だから。
珂朵莉：才不是。是你们太吊儿郎当了，我只是普通而已。
That's not it. You guys are just irresponsible. I'm normal.
ふーん。
艾瑟雅：哼——
Hmm.
クトリ。
艾瑟雅：珂朵莉。
Chtholly.
な、何よ。
珂朵莉：什、什么事。
W-What?
ああ、いや、いい子だなってちょっと思っただけっす。
艾瑟雅：啊，没，只是突然觉得真是个好孩子呢。
Ah, no, I just thought you're a good girl.
え、ええ！？な、なによいきなり。
珂朵莉：诶、诶诶！？怎、怎么突然这么说。
W-What?! Where's this coming from all of a sudden?
心配してくれたんだろう？
艾瑟雅：你刚才是在担心我吧？
You were worried about me, right?
だから、ここはお言葉に甘えておくよ。
艾瑟雅：所以，我就恭敬不如从命了。
So, I'll take you up on your offer.
置きますよ。
奈芙莲：我要放下了。
I'm setting it down.
あ、ああ……
珂朵莉：啊、啊啊……
Oh, right...
アイセア。
奈芙莲：艾瑟雅。
Ithea.
ん、何っすか？ネフレン、何かあった？
艾瑟雅：嗯，怎么了？奈芙莲，有什么事吗？
Hmm, what is it? Nephren, did something happen?
別に、何でもない。
奈芙莲：没什么。
It's nothing.
そう。
艾瑟雅：这样啊。
I see.
んじゃ、あたしはこれで。
艾瑟雅：那，我就先走了。
Well then, I'll be off.
11:04
11:05
何かあったかと聞かれりゃ、そりゃこれ以上ないほど大変なことの最中なんだけど。
艾瑟雅：要是问有没有事，现在我正处于前所未有的大麻烦里呢。
If you ask if something happened, well, I'm right in the middle of a huge mess.
てか本来だったら、すぐに全部管理者に報告すべきなんだろうけどさ。
艾瑟雅：说起来按理说，应该立刻向管理员报告一切才对。
Actually, normally I should report everything to the administrator right away.
ここはとても心地がいい。
艾瑟雅：这里让人感到非常舒适。
It's very comfortable here.
元々あたしが生きていた時代、ネプラカーンには
艾瑟雅：在我原本生活的时代，尼布拉克恩……
In the era I originally lived in, at Neplakhan,
まともな生活なんて許されていなかった。
艾瑟雅：根本不被允许过上像样的生活。
we weren't allowed any semblance of a decent life.
誰かの愛情にただ甘えるなんてこと、できるはずもなかった。
艾瑟雅：撒娇依赖某人的爱这种事，是绝对不可能的。
There was no way we could just indulge in someone's affection.
だから、あと少しでいいから。
艾瑟雅：所以，哪怕再多一会就好。
So, just a little longer.
このままこの場所にいたい。
艾瑟雅：我想继续留在这里。
I want to stay in this place.
もう少しだけ、この借り物の幸せに浸っていたい。
艾瑟雅：想在这一份借来的幸福里，再沉浸一会。
I want to soak in this borrowed happiness just a little bit more.
にしても、すごい数の日記。
艾瑟雅：不过说真的，日记的数量还真惊人。
Still, that's a huge number of diaries.
これ全部一人で書いたってのかね、噂のアイセアちゃんも。
艾瑟雅：这些全是一个人写的吗？传说中的艾瑟雅酱。
Did she write all of these by herself? The rumored Ithea.
そんでもって、
艾瑟雅：然后就是……
And then...
あたしをここに置いて、どこに行っちゃったのかね？
艾瑟雅：把我留在这儿，她又去哪儿了呢？
Where did she go, leaving me here?
4日目、薄々気づき始めていた。
艾瑟雅：第四天，我隐约开始察觉到了。
The fourth day, I was beginning to suspect.
あたしがアイセアの姿をしている理由。
艾瑟雅：我之所以顶着艾瑟雅的样子的理由。
The reason I have Ithea's appearance.
本物のアイセアがどこにもいない理由。
艾瑟雅：真正的艾瑟雅无处可寻的理由。
The reason the real Ithea is nowhere to be found.
気づき始めていたけれど、気づいていないフリをして。
艾瑟雅：虽然察觉到了，却假装没发现。
I was beginning to notice, but I pretended not to.
日記を読み進めた。
艾瑟雅：我继续读着日记。
I kept reading the diary.
5日目。
艾瑟雅：第五天。
The fifth day.
日記を読み進めた。
艾瑟雅：我继续读着日记。
I kept reading the diary.
6日目。7日目。
艾瑟雅：第六天、第七天。
The sixth day. The seventh day.
日記を読み進めた。
艾瑟雅：我继续读着日记。
I kept reading the diary.
そして、知った。
艾瑟雅：然后，我明白了。
And then, I knew.
日記の中、本物のアイセアの悲痛な叫びが綴られている。
艾瑟雅：日记中记录着真正的艾瑟雅悲痛的呼喊。
In the diary, the real Ithea's agonized screams are written.
物忘れが増えた。
艾瑟雅：“忘事变多了。”
"I'm becoming more forgetful."
誰か他人の記憶が浮かぶ。
艾瑟雅：“脑海中浮现出别人的记忆。”
"Memories of someone else come to me."
自分が薄れてきている気がする。
艾瑟雅：“感觉自我的存在正变得稀薄。”
"I feel like I'm fading away."
怖い。
艾瑟雅：“我好害怕。”
"I'm scared."
わけがわからない。
艾瑟雅：“完全不明白是怎么回事。”
"I don't understand what's happening."
なのに誰にも相談できない。
艾瑟雅：“可即便如此，我也无法向任何人倾诉。”
"And yet, I can't talk to anyone about it."
誰も信用できない。
艾瑟雅：“谁都无法信任。”
"I can't trust anyone."
心の中の誰かが、誰のことも信じてはいけないと訴えかけてくる。
艾瑟雅：“内心深处的某个人在告诫我，决不能相信任何人。”
"Someone inside my heart is telling me that I shouldn't trust anyone."
あたしが、消える。
艾瑟雅：“我……快要消失了。”
"I... am disappearing."
これが最後のページで。
艾瑟雅：这就是最后一页。
This is the last page.
先週の日付ってことは。
艾瑟雅：日期是上周，也就是说……
Since the date is from last week...
やっぱりあれか。
艾瑟雅：果然是那样吗。
I knew it.
この体は元々、本物のアイセアのものだ。
艾瑟雅：这具身体原本属于真正的艾瑟雅。
This body originally belonged to the real Ithea.
そしてそのアイセアを、あたしが消したんだ。
艾瑟雅：而那个艾瑟雅，是被我抹杀掉的。
And I'm the one who made that Ithea disappear.
この体を奪って、あたしが。
艾瑟雅：我……夺走了这具身体。
I... stole this body.
殺したんだ。
艾瑟雅：我杀了她。
I killed her.
何の音？て、ちょっとカップ割っちゃったの？
珂朵莉：什么声音？哎，你把杯子打碎了吗？
What was that noise? Wait, did you break a cup?
ああ……クトリ。
艾瑟雅：啊……珂朵莉。
Ah... Chtholly.
あちゃー、それトカのお気に入りだったやつだ。
珂朵莉：啊呀，那是妮戈兰最喜欢的一个杯子。
Oops, that was Nygglatho's favorite.
破片危ないから、君は動かないで。
珂朵莉：碎片很危险，你别动。
The shards are dangerous, so don't move.
お、うん。
艾瑟雅：哦、嗯。
O-Oh, right.
ん、何、この赤いのは？
珂朵莉：嗯？这红红的是什么？
Hmm, what's this red stuff?
うわ、すごい血！君怪我してるじゃない！
珂朵莉：哇，流了好多血！你受伤了啊！
Whoa, that's a lot of blood! You're hurt!
お、本当だ。カップの破片で切ったんですかね。
艾瑟雅：喔，真的。是被杯子的碎片割到了吧。
Oh, you're right. I must have cut myself on the shards.
医務室で手当てしてきなさいよ、床が汚れるし、
珂朵莉：快去医务室包扎一下，地板都被弄脏了。
Go get treated at the infirmary. The floor is getting dirty.
そういうの放っておくとまたナイグラートが悲しい顔するし。
珂朵莉：要是就这么不管，妮戈兰又要露出难过的表情了。
If you leave it like that, Nygglatho will look sad again.
このまま放っておいたら、死んじゃいますかね？
艾瑟雅：如果就这么放着不管，会死掉吗？
If I just leave it like this, will I die?
かもね。だからほら……
珂朵莉：也许吧。所以快……
Maybe. So come on...
そのほうがいいのかもね。
艾瑟雅：那样或许更好呢。
Maybe that would be for the best.
え？
珂朵莉：诶？
Eh?
死んでたはずのあたしが、生きてたはずの子を踏みつけにして今ここにいる。
艾瑟雅：本该死去的我，却践踏着本该活着的女孩，站在这里。
I, who should have died, am here now, treading upon a child who should have lived.
冗談じゃないよ。
艾瑟雅：这可不是在开玩笑。
This isn't a joke.
笑えない。
艾瑟雅：一点也不好笑。
I'm not laughing.
間違いは正さないといけない。
艾瑟雅：错误必须得到修正。
I have to correct this mistake.
ちょっとアイセア、いきなりどうしたの？
珂朵莉：等下艾瑟雅，你突然是怎么了？
Wait Ithea, what's gotten into you all of a sudden?
この子の心は今更取り戻せないとしたも、
艾瑟雅：即使现在已经无法找回这个女孩的心了，
Even if I can't get this child's heart back anymore...
せめてあたしがここで消えれば、死んだはずの者がちゃんと死ねば、
艾瑟雅：至少只要我在这里消失，只要该死的人确实死去，
...if at least I disappear here, if the one who should be dead dies properly,
間違いは半分だけでも取り戻せる。
艾瑟雅：错误至少能挽回一半。
then even if just by half, I can fix the mistake.
ちょっとこら！いきなり自分の世界で考え込まないで。
珂朵莉：喂，等下！别突然一个人陷进自己的世界里思考。
Hey now! Don't suddenly get lost in your own thoughts.
人の話聞きなさいってば。
珂朵莉：给我听别人说话呀。
Listen to what I'm saying.
ほらハンカチ。今すぐ血を止めて。
珂朵莉：诺，手帕。快点止血。
Here, a handkerchief. Stop the bleeding right now.
医務室に行く。早く。
珂朵莉：去医务室。快点。
Go to the infirmary. Hurry.
でも、でもじゃない。
艾瑟雅：可是……没什么可是的。
But— no "buts."
ここで手当てして、ほんのちょっと長生きして、それで何になるっていうのさ？
艾瑟雅：就算在这儿包扎，就算多活那么一丁点儿，又有什么意义呢？
You get treated here, you live just a tiny bit longer, and then what?
本当に生きてるかどうかもよくわからない、ちゃんと死ぬことすらできないとしたら、
艾瑟雅：要是连是否真的活着都搞不清楚，要是连死都死不透的话，
If you don't even know if you're really alive, if you can't even die properly,
ちゃんと生きることなんてできるはずもない。
艾瑟雅：那也就根本不可能好好地活着。
then there's no way you can live properly either.
あたしらの人生に、何の意味があるんだ。
艾瑟雅：我们的人生，到底有什么意义。
What meaning is there in our lives?
少なくとも、あたしにはこの先を生きる権利なんてものはない。
艾瑟雅：至少，我没有继续活下去的权利。
At least, I don't have the right to keep on living.
ここで朽ちて終わるなら、そっちのほうが……
艾瑟雅：如果能在这儿腐朽终结的话，那反而……
If I were to rot away here, it would be...
よくわからないけど、君はここにいるじゃない。
珂朵莉：虽然我听不太懂，但你不是确实在这儿吗。
I don't really get it, but you're here, aren't you?
ほう。
艾瑟雅：喔……
Eh?
生きてるとか死んでるとか、よくわからないし、どうでもいい。
珂朵莉：不管是生是死，我搞不清楚，也无所谓。
Whether you're alive or dead, I don't really know, and it doesn't matter.
でも、君はちゃんとここにいるじゃない。
珂朵莉：但是，你确实好好地在这儿。
But you are definitely here.
だから、これからもここにいていいのよ。
珂朵莉：所以，今后也可以继续留在这儿。
So, you can stay here from now on too.
たぶん。
珂朵莉：大概。
Probably.
そう、なんすかね。
艾瑟雅：是……是这样吗。
I see.
ん？
珂朵莉：嗯？
Hmm?
たぶん。そうなんじゃないかな。
珂朵莉：大概吧。应该是这样的。
Probably. I think so.
よく分かってないけど。
珂朵莉：虽然我也不是很明白。
Though I don't really understand it well.
って、アイセア君、なんで泣いてるの？
珂朵莉：哎，艾瑟雅君，你为什么要哭啊？
Wait, Ithea, why are you crying?
あわわこら！怪我してる手で涙とか拭いたら大変なことに……
珂朵莉：哇哇喂！用受伤的手去擦眼泪的话会出大事……
Awa-wa, hey! If you wipe your tears with your injured hand...
あーもう！大変なことになってるし！
珂朵莉：啊真是的！已经出大事了啦！
Agh, jeez! It's already become a mess!
クトリ。
艾瑟雅：珂朵莉。
Chtholly.
ハンカチ！新しいハンカチはどこ？
珂朵莉：手帕！新的手帕在哪儿？
Handkerchief! Where's a new handkerchief?
やっぱあんた、いい子っすね。
艾瑟雅：果然，你是个好孩子呢。
You really are a good girl.
え、そ、そうかな。
珂朵莉：诶、是、是吗。
Wh-What? You think so?
って、そういう場合じゃなくて。ハンカチ！
珂朵莉：不是说这些的时候啦。手帕！
Now's not the time for that! Handkerchief!
それから2年ほどの時間が流れて。
艾瑟雅：在那之后，大约过了两年。
Two years have passed since then.
ははー！
艾瑟雅：哈——哈！
Haha!
何笑ってるの、アイセア。
珂朵莉：你在笑什么呀，艾瑟雅。
What are you laughing at, Ithea?
あ、いや、思い出し笑いっすよ。
艾瑟雅：啊，没，只是想到往事有点想笑。
Ah, no, I just remembered something and laughed.
昔のクトリは可愛かったなー、みたいな。
艾瑟雅：心想“以前的珂朵莉真可爱呀”之类的。
Like, "Chtholly used to be so cute."
何よそれ。
珂朵莉：什么鬼。
What's that supposed to mean?
本当、君って何考えてるか分からない。
珂朵莉：真是的，完全搞不懂你在想什么。
Honestly, I never know what you're thinking.
2人とも、私語はそこまで。
奈芙莲：你们两个，闲聊到此为止。
You two, that's enough chatting.
今は目の前の敵に集中して。
奈芙莲：现在集中精力对付眼前的敌人。
Focus on the enemy in front of you for now.
うー、今日のまた生きの良さそうなティメレっすね。
艾瑟雅：唔，今天的也是看上去很有活力的第六兽呢。
Ooh, today's Timere looks quite lively too.
強い、かな。
奈芙莲：很强……吗。
Strong... maybe.
やっぱ。
艾瑟雅：果然。
Thought so.
ま、最悪の場合でも、門を開くのはあたしの役目っすよ。
艾瑟雅：嘛，即便在最坏的情况下，开启魔力之门的也是我的职责。
Well, even in the worst-case scenario, opening the gate is my role.
あのサイズのティメレなら、あたしとヴァルガリスで十分お釣りが来る。
艾瑟雅：那个尺寸的第六兽，我和瓦尔卡利斯绰绰有余。
Against a Timere of that size, me and Valgulious are more than enough.
オッケーオッケー。今のは冗談。
艾瑟雅：OKOK。刚才开玩笑的。
Okay, okay. That was a joke.
本当にはやんないっすから、その怖い目、やめるっすよクトリ。
艾瑟雅：我不会真的那么做的啦。珂朵莉，别用那么恐怖的眼神盯着我了。
I won't actually do it, so stop with the scary eyes, Chtholly.
心臓に悪い。
艾瑟雅：对心脏太不好了。
It's bad for the heart.
そういう冗談、嫌い。
珂朵莉：那种玩笑，我最讨厌了。
I hate jokes like that.
本当、この子はあたしをなかなか消させてくれないね。
艾瑟雅：真的，这孩子还真是舍不得让我消失呢。
Really, this girl won't easily let me disappear.
2人とも、お客様が待ってる。
奈芙莲：你们两个，客人在等着了。
You two, the guest is waiting.
空気読めない獣っすね。
艾瑟雅：还真是个不会察言观色的野兽。
That's one beast that can't read the room.
あーもう！決めた。
珂朵莉：啊真是的！决定了。
Ah, geez! I've decided.
なんかもう、心配とか色々全部、これぶっ飛ばしてから考える！
珂朵莉：反正担心的这些那些有的没的，等把它轰飞了再考虑！
I'll worry about all that stuff after I blow this thing away!
ははー！
艾瑟雅：哈——哈！
Haha!
ちょ、ちょっとクトリ、あんまり前に出るもんじゃないっすよ。
艾瑟雅：等、等下珂朵莉，不要冲得那么靠前啊。
W-Wait Chtholly, don't go so far forward.
極端。
奈芙莲：走极端。
Extreme.
あーもう、あたしがフォローに入るから。レンはちょっと後ろから援護。
珂朵莉：啊真是的，我来掩护你。莲就在后面一点支援。
Ah, geez, I'll provide backup. Ren, support from a bit further back.
よろしくっすよ。
艾瑟雅：拜托了。
Count on you.
ん、了解。
奈芙莲：嗯，了解。
Mhm, understood.
本物のアイセアは、幸せになれるはずの子だった。
艾瑟雅：真正的艾瑟雅，本该是个能获得幸福的孩子。
The real Ithea was a girl who should have been happy.
その子をあたしが殺した。
艾瑟雅：是我杀了那个女孩。
I killed that girl.
あたしには幸せになる資格も、惜しまれる資格もない。
艾瑟雅：我既没有获得幸福的资格，也没有被人悼念的资格。
I have no right to be happy, nor do I have the right to be mourned.
けれど、だから。せめて。
艾瑟雅：但是，正因如此。至少。
But that's why... at least...
アイセアが大切にしていた日々を。
艾瑟雅：为了艾瑟雅曾珍视的日常。
...for the days Ithea held dear.
アイセアが幸せにできたはずの姉妹たちを。
艾瑟雅：为了艾瑟雅本该带去幸福的姐妹们。
For the sisters Ithea should have made happy.
あたしが代わりに、この手で守っていこう。
艾瑟雅：就由我来代替她，用这双手去守护。
I will take her place and protect them with these hands.
そう決めた。
艾瑟雅：我已经决定了。
That's what I've decided.
さて、今日も今日とお仕事、頑張っていきますかね！
艾瑟雅：那么，今天的工作也要加油干啦！
Now then, let's do our best at work again today!
おしまい。
剧终。
The End.